还好…
It was...
还好你当时不在
it was good you weren't here for it.
她还好吗？
She hanging in there?
不好
No.
你们要把十字架也拆了吗？
Are you gonna take the cross, too?
如果我们需要的话
If we need it.
他想去亚特兰大 但我接受不了
He wants to go to Atlanta, but I can't have that.
那你留下来 我去
Then you stay. I'll go.
我欠卡萝尔的
I owe it to Carol.
我们都欠卡萝尔的
We all owe Carol.
我欠她的更多
I owe her more.
(你会为此下地狱)
好了
All right.
我们很快就会回来
We'll be back soon.
我知道
I know.
《行尸走肉》
怎么了？
Yeah?
你知道我经历过这种事
You know I've been there.
我知道
I know.
鲍勃 他会希望…
Bob, he would have wanted...
别说了
Don't.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
求你别说了
Please, don't.
好吗？
Okay?
借过
Excuse me.
我只是来检查她
I'm just checking on her.
它们不知道我们在这里
They got no clue we're here.
这对GREATM是个好消息
That's great news for GREATM.
GREATM的一个坏消息是
In less great news for GREATM,
我们分完了最后一点水
we just scraped the bottom of the water barrel.
GREATM是什么
What is... what's GREATM?
我们 小组名字 团结
Us. Group name. Solidarity.
兄弟连
Band of brothers.
GREATM(每个人名的首字母)
GREATM.
我打算在我的指关节弄个纹身
Thinking about getting a tattoo on my knuckles.
抱歉 我只是想分分心
Sorry, I'm just trying to think of something else, you know?
嗯
Yeah.
他醒了吗？
Anything?
没有
No.
我们该送他去教堂吗？
Should we get him to the church?
移动他可能让他情况更糟
Moving him could make him worse.
什么会让他好转？
What will make him better?
醒来
Waking up.
如果他没有…
If he doesn't...
来吧
Come on.
你一整天都没喝水
You haven't had anything to drink all day.
拿着瓶子
Take the bottle.
说真的 我六岁的侄子都不这样做
Seriously, my six- year-old nephew didn't pull this shit.
别这样 亚伯拉罕
Don't do this, Abraham.
- 看着我 - 别惹我
- Look at me! - Don't.
看着我
Look at me!
坐下 不然我崩了你
Sit down or I'll put you down.
那么 接下来该做什么？
Well, what's next on the agenda?
日落时分 我们朝天空开一枪
At sundown we fire a shot into the air.
引两个人出来巡逻
Get two of them out on patrol.
等天黑了
Then once it's dark enough
房顶上的人看不见我们时 就行动
that the rooftop spotter won't see us, we go.
把一侧楼梯的锁破坏掉
We cut the locks on one of the stairways,
上到五楼
take it to the fifth floor.
我开门 达里尔干掉守卫
I open the door, Daryl takes the guard out.
怎么干掉？
How?
一刀封喉
He slits his throat.
这次行动必须安静 占据优势
This is all about us doing this quiet, keeping the upper hand.
他们不知道我们会来
They're not expecting us.
上楼后分开行动 使用刀具和消音武器
From there, we fan out. Knives and silenced weapons.
速度一定要快
We need to be fast.
泰尔西 萨莎 干掉他们
Tyreese, Sasha, take them.
达里尔 厨房里的人交给你
Daryl, you take care of whoever is in the kitchen.
道恩交给我
I got Dawn.
如果他们识相 剩下的人就会投降
If they're smart, the rest of them will give up.
那就是5对3了
Then it'll be five on three.
给贝丝一把武器 就是6对3了
Six on three once we get a weapon to Beth.
是12对3 病人们会帮我们
12 on three. The wards will help.
这是最好的打算 那最差的呢？
That's best case. What's worst case?
如果有一个警察
All it takes is one of those cops
在错误的时间下了楼
going down the hall at the wrong time.
那就没法安静了 全员火并
Then it's not quiet. All hands on deck.
就得真枪实弹硬来了
We're talking about a lot of bullets flying around.
- 也只能硬来了 - 不见得
- If that's what it takes. - It's not.
如果我们能在外面
If we get a couple of her cops
活捉她的手下 就可以跟他们换人
alive out here, we do an even trade.
他们的人换我们的人 大家各回各家
Theirs for ours. Everybody goes home.
我明白
Yeah, I get it.
那招说不定管用
And it might work.
但是这招一定管用
This will work.
不 那招也管用
Nah, that'll work, too.
你不是说道恩只是想让一切正常运转吗？
You say this Dawn, she's just trying to keep it together, right?
理想和现实是两码事
Trying and doing are two different things.
抓走她的两名警察
You take two of her cops away,
她还能有什么能耐？
what choices does she have?
大家都会各回各家
Everybody goes home.
就像他说的
Like he says.
选一个
Pick one.
你要学会自卫
You need to learn how to defend yourself.
我们可以教你
We can teach you.
自卫？
Defend myself?
他们都说会离开了
They said they'd go.
他们是骗子 杀人凶手
They were liars and murderers.
- 我们也是 - 我们那是自保
- Just like us. - We protected ourselves.
他们想杀我们
They wanted us dead.
你的教堂能撑这么久是运气好
You're lucky your church has lasted this long.
如今你不能在一个地方久留
You can't stay in one place anymore.
不能待太久
Not for too long.
一旦你离开这里
And once you're out there,
就会遇到无可避免的麻烦
you're gonna find trouble you can't hide from.
你必须学会如何战斗
You need to know how to fight.
不错的选择
Good choice.
但握法不对
But you're not holding it right.
你必须能捅下去
You've got to be able to drive it down
因为有时候它们的头骨
Because sometimes their skulls
有点硬 你必须能…
aren't as soft and you need to be able...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不行
No.
我得躺一会儿
I need to lie down.
这就是你的计划？
That's your plan, huh?
听着 我们已经尽力了
Look, we are doing everything we can.
莉卡瑞现在还在开着车找
Licari is out in the sedan right now.
如果有诺亚的踪迹 我们会找到他的
If there is a sign of Noah, we are going to find him.
你刚说过 你的计划是指望着他自己遇险
You just told me that your plan was counting on him screwing up.
身为警察 你办事还真是靠谱
That's some active police work right there.
还有别的事吗？
Was there anything else?
是的 还真有
Yes, actually, there was.
在二号诊室的病人
The patient in exam room two,
我把她带回来的时候 她已经半死了
she was half dead when I brought her in.
她的情况不太乐观
She's not looking so good.
这不是竹篮打水的游戏
This ain't Pin the Tail On the Donkey.
我们真要在这个女人身上浪费资源吗？
Are we really gonna keep wasting valuable resources on this lady?
你的DVD要用多少电？
How much electricity does your DVD take?
- 你说什么？- 我们的资源很有限
- Excuse me? - We have very limited resources here.
而你每天都给它充电
You charge it every day.
- 你开玩笑吗？ - 贝丝
- Are you kidding me? - Beth.
- 那个女人才来这里一天 - 贝丝
- That woman has been here one day. - Beth.
如果这地方连救人也做不到 它还有什么好呢？
What good is this place if it doesn't try to save people?
关闭设备
Turn off the machines.
告诉爱德华兹不用再检查那个病人了
Tell Edwards to take the patient off of his rounds.
如果她自己挺过来了 很好
If she pulls through on her own, then fine.
但是你说得对 她不值得再付出资源了
But you're right. She's not worth the effort.
是你害死了那个女人
You just killed that woman.
你以为我敢站在你一边吗？
Who do you think I have to side with?
跟他说 你改变主意了
Tell him. Tell him you changed your mind.
你不知道我的统治有多脆弱
You don't know how fragile this thing is.
我无能为力
There's nothing I can do.
所以必须由你来做
So you'll just have to do it.
你去救那个女人
You're gonna save that woman's life.
这是药物储藏室的钥匙
This is to the drug locker.
我都不放心交给爱德华兹
I don't even trust Edwards with this.
你拿好
So take it.
我是夏普德 我在屋顶站岗
It's Shepherd. I'm on roof detail.
北东北方向一英里处传来了枪声
Just heard a gunshot maybe a mile north- northeast.
叫上拉姆森 开辆车去看看
Grab Lamson, take a car and track it down.
遵命 长官
Yes, ma'am.
你为什么要这样做？
Why are you doing this?
我之前以为你很弱
I thought you were weak.
但你用实际行动证明了我是错的
You've proved me wrong.
我们需要更多的水
We need more water.
路前面的西南方有条小溪
There's a creek up the road
离这里只有几英里
a few miles southwest of here.
你们都去吧 我留在这里
You all go. I'll stay here.
你确定？
You sure?
是的
I am.
好吧
Okay.
待着别动 伙计们 别起来
Just stay here, guys. Don't get up.
华盛顿没什么可给你们的
There is nothing for you in Washington.
一点都不好笑
That's not funny.
也不是一点都不好笑
It's not not not not funny.
我知道我们都有自己的应对方法…
Hey, I get that we're all dealing with things in different ways...
听着 华盛顿泡汤了 我不知该怎么办
Listen, I don't know what to do without DC anymore,
但我并没有应对什么 我已经走出来了
but I'm not dealing with it. I'm over it.
我只是希望他一切安好
I just want him to be okay.
尤金不够强壮
Eugene wasn't strong.
速度不够快 连武器都不会用
He isn't fast. He doesn't know how to use a weapon.
真相是残酷的 但他确实是个没用的人
The truth hurts, but he's useless.
他拥有一项得以保命的能力
He had one skill that kept him living.
因为他加以利用 我们就该生他的气吗？
Are we supposed to be mad at him 'cause he used it?
太他妈对了
Damn right.
你够了
Get over yourself.
今天不只你一个人失去了重要的东西
You're not the only one who lost something today.
一切不可能变得比现在更好了
It's never gonna get any better than this.
贝丝
Beth.
我可以进去吗？
Can I?
当然
Yeah, sure.
在二号诊室的那个女人
The woman in exam room two,
你会给她用什么药？
what medicine would you give her?
道恩下令停止治疗了
Dawn called it.
我知道 但如果可以 你会用什么药？
I know, but if you could, what would you give her?
她遭遇了车祸 受了内伤
She was in a car accident. She suffered internal injuries.
我只能大概猜猜
It's just a guessing game.
那就猜吧
So guess.
你有钥匙
You have the key.
是你偷来的 还是她给你的？
Did you take it or did she give it to you?
如果钥匙是她给你的
Because if she gave it to you, she did not do it
- 她绝对没安好心 - 别说了
- out of the kindness of her heart. - Don't.
告诉我用什么药就好
Just tell me what medicine.
我那样做是想保命
I was trying to save my life.
我依然不知道是否保住了
I'm still wondering if I did.
肾上腺素滴注 五毫克
Epinephrine drip, five milligrams.
她不会马上醒来
She won't wake up right away,
但是这会缓解她的血压
but it'll ease her blood pressure
这样她就有生存的机会
so she'll have a shot.
祝你好运
Good luck.
真棒
Perfect.
你觉得上游的水会清澈一些吗？
You think it's any clearer upstream?
应该不会
Probably not.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
让我看看
Let me see.
你在两分钟内就做好了一个滤水器啊？
So, you just built a water filter in about two minutes, huh?
尤金教我的
Eugene taught me.
这需要一些时间 但水会清澈的
Takes a while, but it'll be clear.
然后我们可以烧水
Then we can boil it.
灾变之前 你和亚伯拉罕在一起吗？
Were you with Abraham before it all happened?
没有
No.
没有 我跟别人在一起 努力生存下去
No, I was with other people just trying to make it.
你们怎么到一起的？
How'd you wind up together?
我们在达拉斯遇上了
We crossed paths in Dallas.
我和我的团队在击退行尸
Me and my group, we were fighting off some dead ones
他开着大卡车 不知道从哪里
and he jumped in from out of nowhere
冒了出来
with that big truck.
愿那辆卡车安息
Rest in peace.
尤金在驾驶室里
He had Eugene in the cab.
之后 他告诉我 他在拯救世界
And afterwards, he told me that he was trying to save the world.
他看到了我的能力
And that he saw what I could do.
他需要我的帮助
And he wanted my help.
自从灾变之后 他是第一个
He was the first person to ask me for that
寻求我帮助的人
since this all started.
也许他也在撒谎
Maybe he was lying, too.
看见了吗？
You see that?
那些波纹
Those ripples.
是鱼
Those are fish.
好吧 怎么做？
Okay, how?
来吧
Come on.
枪声是从那边传出的
Shots were from over there.
我对天发誓我听到了
I swear to God I heard it.
那边 那边
There. There!
- 放下 诺亚 - 放下枪
- Put it down, Noah. - Put the gun down.
举起手来
Hands up.
转身
Turn around.
觉得太紧了就告诉我 好吗？
You let me know if it's too tight, okay?
我还以为你很聪明 诺亚
I thought you were smart, Noah.
你觉得我们听不到吗？
You think we wouldn't hear you?
你射击的行尸呢？
Where are those rotters you were shooting at?
举起手来
Hands.
你们想怎么样？
What do you want?
不管你们要干什么
Whatever this is,
我们都可以帮忙的
we can help.
按我们说的做 我们就不伤害你们
You do what we say, we don't hurt you.
好吧
Okay.
很好 现在转过身去
Good. Now turn around.
把枪放在地上 然后跪下
Put your guns on the floor and kneel.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
假如你们需要的话 这儿有水和食物
There's water if you need some and food.
介意我问你一件事吗？
Mind if I ask you something?
你说话的方式…
The way you talk...
你举手投足之间…
the way you carry yourself...
你之前是警察吗？
were you a cop?
信不信由你 我以前也是
Believe it or not, I was, too.
那是拉姆森
That's Lamson.
他会支持我们的
He'll be down for this.
他是个好人
He's one of the good ones.
(疏散区)
两个 我来
Two, on me.
(联邦应急管理局)
好吧
Okay.
你赢了 混蛋
You win, asshole.
瑞克
Rick.
Rick!
瑞克
Rick,
三个人总比两个好
three is better than two.
你们的朋友 他叫什么？
Your friend, what's his name?
我得和他谈谈
I need to talk to him.
你们的计划会害死我和我朋友的
Your plan is going to get me and my friends killed.
我们会成功的
We're gonna make it work.
前提是你得有别的警察来交换
It would work if you had different cops to trade.
道恩把格拉迪医院管得一团糟
Dawn's running Grady into the ground.
我们中有一些人想让她下台 她自己也清楚
A bunch of us want her out and she knows it.
我很确定她也知道我们想让拉姆森来取代她
Pretty sure she knows we want Lamson to replace her, too.
道恩不知道这个
Dawn doesn't know that.
她可能知道
She might.
而且她很聪明
And she's smart.
所以你们的交易很可能失败
So there's a good chance you can't make this deal work
这会让我们全部送命
and that'll leave us all dead.
但假如你让我们走的话
But if you let us go,
我们会自己解决了道恩
we'll take care of Dawn ourselves
然后我们会放走你的朋友们 这事就结了
and then we'll let your friends go and this is over.
不 我们不会这么做的
No, we're not gonna do that.
- 你想死吗？ - 不想
- Do you want to die? - No.
我只是需要你马上闭嘴
I just need you to shut up right now.
你们可以成功的
You can make this work.
但是你们得先和她通上话
But you've got to be able to talk to her.
诺亚告诉了我们关于她的一切
Noah told us all about her.
我认识她八年了 女士
I've known her for eight years, ma'am.
我了解这个女人
I know this woman.
我只想和平解决此事
And my only interest is peaceful resolution,
活下去
not dying,
今晚睡在我自己的床上
and sleeping in my bed tonight.
所以 求你们了
So, please,
让我帮你们吧
let me help you.
求你们了
Please.
瑞克 来
Hey, Rick.
你会想听听这个的
You're gonna want to hear this.
罗西塔
Rosita.
你那边怎么样 塔拉？
Hey, how are we doing over there, Tara?
很不错 你们呢？
Pretty damn good. How about you?
一个十字螺丝刀
A screwdriver. Phillips head.
快了
Almost.
差不多了
就现在
Now.
- 太棒了 - 管用了
- Hell, yes. - It worked.
不错
Nice.
你知道怎么洗吗？
You know how to clean these things?
我知道
I know how to clean these things.
太好了 我们需要这项能力
Good, we're gonna need that.
无论我们最后去哪里 你加入吗？
Wherever we all wind up. You in?
我加入
I'm in.
- 太好了 - 伙计们
- Good. - Guys.
包里的东西肯定会让你们大吃一惊
You will never believe what's in this bag.
怎么了？
Yes?
你…
You, uh...
你刚才说自己不舒服
you said you weren't feeling good.
你还好吗？
You doing okay?
没事 我只是休息一下
Yeah, I was just resting.
我知道你没经历过这种事
I know all this is new to you.
这一切
All of it.
我只想告诉你
I just wanted to tell you,
想让你知道…
for you to know...
我们做的事…
the things that we do...
值得去做
they're worth it.
我已经拿了砍刀 你还想让我怎么样？
I already took the machete. What more do you want from me?
我不是想让你怎样
I don't want anything from you.
我只是想帮你
I'm just trying to help.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们来了 快来
Here you go. Come on.
- 我喘不了… - 没事吧？
- I can't... I can't... - You all right?
- 我喘不上气了 - 快去叫爱德华兹
- I can't breathe. - Get Edwards now.
- 你去取张轮床 - 好的
- You, get a gurney. - I got it.
没事 看着我
It's okay. Look at me.
- 看着我 - 放松
- Look at me. - Take it easy.
呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
好了 放松 放松
All right. Easy, easy.
保持清醒
Stay with me.
呼吸
Breathe.
我没事了
I... I'm okay.
我也不知道怎么回事 谢谢你们
I don't know what that was. Thank you.
卡萝尔
Carol.
我是贝丝
It's Beth.
我只是想告诉你我在这里
I just wanted you to know that I was here.
我要说出来 你好好听着
I'm gonna say it and you're gonna listen.
等你准备好了 就让我帮你
And then, when you're ready, you let me help you.
你跟他道别过了
You got to say good- bye.
他看到了 也感受到了
He saw it. He felt it.
你现在想纠结哪点都行
And you hold onto whatever you want to,
但我觉得你应该铭记这点
but I think you should hold onto that.
我本应该自己下手的
I should have been able to do it myself.
你是可以
You could've.
但你让自己去感受了
But you let yourself feel it.
睁开眼睛直面了一切
Kept your eyes open.
你让我帮你了
You let me help you.
她会说她不做交易
She'll tell you she won't make a deal.
她会说她绝不妥协
She'll tell you she won't compromise.
但她会的
But she will.
她总是妥协
She always does.
总之 知己知彼
Just... just know who you're talking to.
我们大概十分钟后出发
Probably heading out in the next 10 minutes or so.
我们走之前你需要什么吗？
Anything you need before we leave?
给我点水就好了
Actually, water would be great.
没问题
Will do.
谢谢 拉姆森警官
Thanks, Sergeant Lamson.
我叫鲍勃
My name's Bob.
你依然是个警察
You're still a cop.
不是
No.
不 真的警察都死了
No, the real ones are all gone.
该死
Damn it.
我没事
I'm... I'm okay.
我会没事的
I'll be okay.
我也是
Me, too.
停车场里
The parking lot,
你带我们回这儿的时候 我看见一只行尸
when you were bringing us back up here I... I saw a rotter.
我看到其中一只行尸 我认识他
I saw one of the rotters and I knew him.
他叫泰勒
His name was Tyler.
我在格拉迪见过他
I met him at Grady.
我们都是在灾变后被派到那里的
We were both sent there when shit started going down.
整整两天才疏散完所有人
It took two whole days to evacuate everyone.
没有睡觉 没有吃饭
Didn't sleep. We didn't eat.
但那依然是我这辈子最美好的两天
But still, it was the two best days of my life.
我本该开车
I was supposed to drive
把最后一车幸存者载到安全区
the last van of survivors to the zone
道恩没让我去
and Dawn pulled me off.
她想要她真正信任的人开车
She wanted someone she could really trust
于是她派了泰勒去
and she put Tyler on it instead.
那些人都将疏散
These... these people were gonna all be evacuated.
我很生气
I was really pissed.
我刚在外面看到了他
I saw him out there.
浑身溶化 黏在柏油路上
Stuck out there, melted to the asphalt.
而我能想到的只是
And all I could think was,
"那本该是我
"That would have been me.
那本该是我 他救了我的命"
It would have been me. He saved my life."
这么久以来 他一直在那里
He's been out there the whole time.
变成了街道的一部分
Like he's a part of the street.
就像某种荒谬的 永无止境的笑话
Some screwed up, endless joke.
而我对此无能为力
And there's nothing I can do about it.
那就让我帮你吧
So let me help you.
你还记得他在哪里吗？
Do you remember where he was?
记得 我可以带你去找他
Yeah, I... I can take you right to him.
我们不出去了 但我枪法不错
We're not going out there, but I'm a good shot.
告诉我在哪里
Show me.
好的
Okay.
大楼南面
South side of the building.
在那里能看到他
You can see him from in there.
你渴了
You're thirsty.
别说自己不渴
Don't say you're not.
你刚才想让我开枪杀了你吗？
Did you want me to shoot you?
我以为我想
I thought I did.
但我不想
But I didn't.
有人吗？
Hell... hello?
我来了
I'm coming.
待在原地 不要动
Stay right there. Don't try to move.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
你知道吗？ 我又想了想
You know, the more I think about it,
也许那并不是完全
maybe it wasn't completely
一点也不好笑
not not not funny.
喂
Hey.
别看了
Don't even look at it.
(请依法系好安全带)
你看到他了吗？
You see him?
大概在轿车右边20码处
About 20 yards right of the sedan.
那里有半面墙
There's a half wall.
他就靠在上面
He's leaning against it.
我看到他了
I see him.
你确定是他吗？
Are you sure that's him?